A Guide to the Sutton Family Papers, 1769-1859
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Sutton Family Papers, 1769-1859
The Library of Virginia
22813
22 leaves, negative photostats
Sutton Family
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Lent for copying, March 1948, by Mrs. E. T. Howerton.
Biographical Information
Stephen Sutton (14 March 1786-2 December 1840) was the son of Joesph Sutton (1764-1823) and Judith Carter Sutton (1769-1827) of Caroline County, Virginia. Becoming a doctor, he served as a hospital surgeon mate from 1812 to 1814 during the War of 1812. Afer the war, he settled in Hanover County, Virginia, and married Eliza M. Oliver (1800-1867) 30 May 1816. Sutton bought Towinque in King William County from James Lyons (1764-1830) of Richmond, Virginia, in 1819. The Suttons had 7 children: Laura (d. 1852); David (d. 1892), who also was a physician and settled in Lexington, Mississippi; Pulaski, who served as a private in Co. H, 9th Virginia Cavalry; Elvira M. (d. 1857); Armistead Oliver; Stephen Carter (1822-1880), who served in as a private in Southall's Battery; and Mary Eliza, who married 1st Samuel Hamlet and 2nd Edwin Shelton.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1769-1859, of the Sutton family of Hanover and King William Counties, Virginia, consisting of correspondence, 1771-1859, containing letters, 1771, to David Whitlock of Hanover County discussing business and his crops; letter, 1816, to David Oliver (d. 1822) of Hanover County concerning personal matters; letters, 1818-1825, to Stephen Sutton (1786-1840) of Hanover County regarding property purchases; and letter, 1859, to Stephen C. Sutton (1822-1880) of King William County concerning personal matters. Papers also include deed, 28 December 1769, for 200 acres in Hanover County; will, 30 September 1822, of David Oliver; agreement, 10 January 1854, between members of the Sutton family; and declaration, no date, of James Taylor Sutton (1791-1864) against Philip Bickerham Winston (1786-1853) and Eliza M. Sutton (1800-1867) in Hanover County Circuit Superior Court of Law and Chancery.
Contents List
- Deed, dated 28 December 1769 and recorded February 1770, for 200 acres in Hanover County from Thomas Haden and Mary Haden to Benjamin Oliver (1738-1818), all of Hanover County.
- Letter, 16 February 1771, from Edward Harford of Bristol, England, to David Whitlock of Hanover County, concerning business.
- Letter, 30 May 1771, from Samuel Gist of London, England, to Whitlock regarding Whitlock's crops.
- Letter, 3 August 1816, from C. Brooke of Frederick County, Virginia, to David Oliver (d. 1822) of Hanover County, containing personal news.
- Letter, 12 September 1818, from Isaac Garretson to Dr. Stephen Sutton (1786-1840) of Hanover County discussing the purchase price of property.
- Letter, 22 January 1822, from James Lyons (1801-1882) of Richmond, Virginia, to Sutton concerning the purchase of property in King William County, Virginia.
- Will, dated 30 September 1822 and recorded 23 October 1822, of David Oliver.
- Letter, 27 November 1825, from Lyons to Sutton.
- Agreement, dated 10 January 1854 and acknowledged 13 January 1854, between Eliza M. Sutton (1800-1867) on one part and David Sutton (d. 1892), Stephen C. Sutton (1822-1880), Pulaski Sutton, Elvira Sutton (d. 1857), Armistead O. Sutton, and Mary Eliza Hamlet, all of King William County.
- Letter, 11 October 1859, from David Sutton of Lexington, Mississippi, to Stephen Sutton containing personal and local news.
- Declaration, no date, of James Taylor Sutton (1791-1864) against Philip Bickerton Winston (1786-1853) and Eliza M. Sutton, made in the Circuit Superior Court of Law and Chancery in Hanover County.